eyewonderlabs.com 2013-06-29

# EyeWonder

EyeWonder, LLC and its subsidiaries, collectively referred to as "EyeWonder", provides online advertising services that enable its customers to deliver rich media advertising campaigns, to serve targeted advertising and to receive aggregated reporting data about online advertising campaigns. EyeWonder, in the provision of such services, is committed to protecting online privacy for website users, clients, agencies, advertisers, portals, networks and publishers.

**Network Advertising Initiative**

EyeWonder is a member of the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). ("NAI") and conforms to its standards. The NAI offers a consumer opt-out page and other privacy tools and resources.

|   
---|---  
  
Below is EyeWonder's policy on collecting, using, disclosing, maintaining, and protecting the information generated through EyeWonder®-powered advertisements or through its World Wide Web site (the "Site").

**About this Policy**

This policy is divided into two parts:

  * _Part 1 describes the information EyeWonder collects through EyeWonder®-powered advertisements_ \- for example, when users visit a website that has partnered with EyeWonder to serve EyeWonder®-powered advertisements, or when users click on EyeWonder®-powered advertisements. 
  * _Part 2 describes the information that EyeWonder collects about users through the Site_ \- for example, when users choose to visit, browse and/or submit information through the EyeWonder Site.

**Part 1: Collection of information through EyeWonder®-powered advertisements**

This Part describes only the information EyeWonder collects through EyeWonder®-powered advertisements. It does not describe the information that EyeWonder collects about users that choose to visit the EyeWonder Site, which is instead described in Part 2 ("Information collection through the EyeWonder Site") below.

_A. Information collected by EyeWonder to deliver EyeWonder®-powered advertisements_

In the course of delivering an advertisement to a user on behalf of an advertiser, publisher, portal, network or other such client, EyeWonder does not collect any information that enables a user to be identified as an individual, such as name, address, phone number, or email address or any sensitive information such as financial or health information. However, EyeWonder does collect certain other anonymous information about users who visit websites that have partnered with EyeWonder, such as the server into which a computer is logged, whether and how a user responded to the advertisement delivered, the type of computer operating system used, the date and time of the user's activity and the user's browser type. EyeWonder collects and uses this information (and information derived from it), to create interest 'segments' on behalf of advertisers that reflect users' expressed and inferred interests (for example, interest segments relating to "travel", "sport" or "computing"). Where instructed by its clients, EyeWonder may then use these interest segments for the purpose of serving targeted advertisements on behalf of its clients to users on partnering websites and also to measure the effectiveness of those advertisements.

When an EyeWonder®-powered advertisement is served on behalf of a client to a computer or other electronic device, EyeWonder utilizes techniques to determine whether that device has previously received the advertisement, as well as techniques to evaluate the user's interaction with the advertisement. Such information is used to avoid sending repetitive advertising to the user, to customize subsequent advertising to enhance the user's experience, to comport with the user's habits or preferences, and sometimes to measure the effectiveness of the advertisement.

You can opt-out of receiving rich media or targeted advertising by following the instructions under the heading 'User choices' at section H of this Part 1 below.

_B. Additional information collected by EyeWonder on behalf of advertisers, publishers, networks or portals_

From time to time, advertisers, publishers, networks or portals may request that EyeWonder assist with the collection of information voluntarily supplied by users in connection with an EyeWonder®-powered advertisement, or a user's interaction with such an advertisement, on their behalf. This may include personal information such as name, address, phone number, or email address. EyeWonder provides this information to the advertiser, publisher, network, and/or portal, and does not use it for its own independent purposes. EyeWonder cannot control the use of this voluntarily supplied information by the advertiser, publisher, network, and/or portal, which will be in accordance with its own particular privacy policy. Consequently, EyeWonder is not responsible for the use of such information by the advertiser, publisher, network, and/or portal.

_C. Cookies_

EyeWonder uses "cookies" or "scripts" to enhance a user's experience on the Internet. A cookie is a small text file served by EyeWonder and stored by a user's web browser. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to website owners and service providers.

EyeWonder cookies contain a unique number that is assigned to a browser by EyeWonder the first time an EyeWonder®-powered advertisement is served. This number is stored on the user's computer and helps deliver advertisements which are not repetitive and may be more relevant to the user. This number cannot be transferred to another browser, cannot be related to a specific person, and does not contain viruses. Additionally cookies may collect the types of information about users described in Part 1A above, although this will not include any information that enables any user to be identified as an individual. EyeWonder does not use flash cookies or Local Shared Objects to collect any information about individuals.

Users have the right to choose whether or not to accept cookies. Users can exercise this right by amending or setting the controls on their Internet browser settings to reflect their cookie and script preferences; however, some functionalities of an EyeWonder®-powered advertisement may not be available without the use of cookies and scripts. As the means by which users can do this vary from browser-to-browser, users should visit their browser's help menu for further details. 

EyeWonder sets cookies to expire after eight weeks and the expiration date updates every time a user's browser encounters the EyeWonder server.

EyeWonder offers users the ability to control the placement of EyeWonder adserving cookies for the purpose of serving rich media or targeted advertising, as described in section H of this Part 1 headed 'User choices' below.

_D. Data collected by Third Parties_

Sites of EyeWonder advertiser clients as well as the publishers of sites on which advertisements are placed may also collect information from users. Such information may include non-personally identifiable information through the use of cookies and other technology as well as personally identifiable information about a user who registers or transacts with, or otherwise uses, any such website. EyeWonder is not responsible for the privacy practices of websites operated by such third parties. Users should check the applicable privacy policies of such websites to determine what information is collected and how such information is used.

_E. Data provided by Third Parties_

From time-to-time, EyeWonder may also use data from third party data providers. Data acquired from third party data providers may include anonymous behavioral information that those providers have themselves licensed, purchased or collected. EyeWonder may use this data to provide or enhance the services it provides to its clients, such as targeted advertising services, but will at all times use and protect such data in accordance with this privacy policy.

_F. Data Sharing_

EyeWonder services are used by its clients, which include agencies, advertisers, publishers and other companies, to provide online advertising and create anonymized, aggregated reporting information about the performance of online advertising campaigns. Such aggregated reporting information is shared with clients and their authorized third parties for their own reporting and analytics purposes.

Additionally, EyeWonder may share information it obtains from individuals in the course of providing rich media or targeted advertising services as follows:

  1. Where EyeWonder believes disclosure is necessary for the purpose of complying with government disclosure requirements, subpoenas, search warrants, applicable laws or other lawful requests for information or where EyeWonder believes disclosure is otherwise necessary to establish, exercise or defend legal rights
  2. With vendors, services providers and other technology providers that act on EyeWonder's behalf to enable it to provide services to its clients
  3. With other members of the EyeWonder group of companies for internal reporting purposes and so that they may provide services to their clients
  4. For Any Other Lawful Purpose

_G. Data Security and Retention_

EyeWonder uses appropriate technical and organizational measures to maintain the security of data collected through EyeWonder®-powered advertisements. Such measures have been implemented to protect information from unauthorized or unlawful access, use or disclosure and against accidental loss, damage or destruction. Access to data is restricted to authorized individuals. Security audits are conducted and overseen by independent third parties.

While EyeWonder takes commercially reasonable steps to ensure security, EyeWonder cannot guarantee that data will not be accessed by accidental circumstances or by the unauthorized acts of others.

After EyeWonder completes the provision of targeted advertising services to a client, it will generally retain information collected in the course of those services for up to 90 days or a shorter period where required by law or contractual obligations. In any case, it is never retained for more than 2 years.

Additionally, as part of the online advertising services provided by EyeWonder, EyeWonder collects and shares anonymized aggregated reporting information as described in section F of this Part 1. This limited type of anonymized, aggregated reporting information may be kept indefinitely.

_H. User Choices_

Users always have the right to control whether or not they wish to receive cookies served by EyeWonder. If a user would like to control the use of EyeWonder cookies for the purpose of serving rich media or targeted advertising, then the user can click on the appropriate Opt-In or Opt-Out link below. Users that have previously opted-out and would like to opt back in to receiving rich media or targeted advertising served by EyeWonder can click on the Opt-In link below.

Click "Save" to accept your settings.

To record a user's opt-out preferences, EyeWonder needs to provide an opt-out cookie to the user's browser. Therefore, if cookies are disabled, erased, or altered, or browser or machine software is changed, then the results of this opt-out process may be undone and the user will need to opt-out again by revisiting this page and re-submitting its opt-out preference.

Alternatively, users can visit the NAI website for information about how to control the service of adserving cookies served by EyeWonder and other advertisers, publishers and ad networks that are members of the NAI. For more information, please click here: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

In addition to the above, users may also control the use of cookies through setting or changing their web browser controls. Cookies may be deleted or controlled by configuring the web browser. Information about configuring the browser can be found in the help section of the browser. However, as described above, please note that changing a web browser's controls to delete cookies will also erase any opt-out preference cookies previously served to a user's computer, meaning that a user may need to re-visit this page to refuse rich media or targeted advertising by EyeWonder.

_I. International processing_

If you are an individual resident in the European Economic Area, please be aware that, in some instances, EyeWonder may process the information it collects in the United States. However, users' information will always be protected in accordance with strict data security standards wherever it is processed.

_J. Third party privacy practices_

This Part 1 applies solely to information collected by EyeWonder through EyeWonder®-powered advertisements. EyeWonder is not responsible for the privacy practices of advertisers, publishers, networks or portals on whose sites EyeWonder®-powered advertisements may be served, and as such, the privacy policies of that party apply.

Some of these third parties may be advertising service providers who are members of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI"). Where this is the case, a user can obtain information about these advertising service providers' information collection practices, and opt out of such practices (and, at the same time, opt out of the collection practices of other, or all, NAI members) by following the opt out instructions on the NAI's website at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

_K. Children's Privacy Statement_

EyeWonder does not collect information that would enable it to identify a user as an individual. As such, it does not knowingly collect any information from or about children under the age of 13.

Consequently, EyeWonder does not intentionally target advertising at children under the age of 13. However, because EyeWonder does not collect information enabling it to identify any user as an individual (and therefore does not know the age of any user), there may be instances where EyeWonder inadvertently collects browsing information from under 13s when they use other users' web browsers.

However, EyeWonder will delete information it holds about any user under the age of 13 when it is made aware that it has inadvertently received any such information. If you believe this may be the case with respect to any child for whom you are responsible, please contact EyeWonder using the details provided below.

**Part 2: Information collection through the EyeWonder Site**

This Part describes only the information EyeWonder collects about users that choose to visit the EyeWonder Site. It does not describe the information that EyeWonder collects through EyeWonder®-powered advertisements, which is instead described in Part 1 ("Collection of information through EyeWonder®-powered advertisements") above.

Information collected through the Site varies, depending on the sections of the Site visited and the information the visitor chooses to provide. For visitors to the public sections of the Site who read or download information, EyeWonder collects only limited information about their visit which does not enable them to be identified as individuals. This includes information about the IP address of the visitor's computer, the visitor's type of computer and operating system, the date and time of access, and the URL of the website from which the visitor linked directly to the Site. EyeWonder does not collect any information from visitors who visit only the public sections of the Site that enables them to be identified as individuals.

For visitors who contact EyeWonder via e-mail or who participate in an online survey, the information provided in the e-mail message or survey response is collected, including the visitor's e-mail address, and any questions or comments the visitor provides.

Information that EyeWonder collects through the Site is used for its internal business purposes, including studying the use of the Site, and may be disclosed to other companies within the EyeWonder group of companies which includes EyeWonder's parent, subsidiaries and affiliates (the " **EyeWonder Group** ") and to third party service providers who supply services to the EyeWonder Group. If a question or comment is sent to EyeWonder by e-mail, EyeWonder uses the information therein to respond to the question or comment. EyeWonder also may use the information provided to it to send news and information about the EyeWonder Group that it believes may be of interest, and in accordance with users' expressed contact preferences. In addition, EyeWonder may disclose information concerning the Site and its visitors in an aggregate, anonymised form.

EyeWonder uses appropriate technical and organizational measures to maintain the security of data collected through the Site. Such measures have been implemented to protect information from unauthorized or unlawful access, use or disclosure and against accidental loss, damage or destruction. Access to data is restricted to authorized individuals. Security audits are conducted and overseen by independent third parties.

While EyeWonder takes commercially reasonable steps to ensure security, EyeWonder cannot guarantee that data will not be accessed by accidental circumstances or by the unauthorized acts of others.

Additionally, EyeWonder cannot guarantee that submissions to the Site, or that any content residing on or transmissions from, EyeWonder's servers will be completely secure. No Internet transmission can ever be guaranteed 100% safe, and users should take reasonable precautions when connecting to and surfing the Internet (including the use of appropriate firewall and anti-virus software).

Any password-protected areas of the Site can be accessed only with a valid password. Each password owner is responsible for keeping the password secret and confidential, and for notifying EyeWonder if the password may have been stolen or might otherwise be misused.

If a visitor has elected to receive from EyeWonder product updates, new product information, newsletters, or other marketing information, and would like to discontinue receiving these materials, send an email to optout@eyewonder.com with "privacy policy opt-out" in the subject line. EyeWonder does not send unsolicited marketing e-mails to anyone who has asked not to be contacted by EyeWonder.

_A. Disclosures of information_

EyeWonder may share information collected through the Site as follows:

  1. Where EyeWonder believes disclosure is necessary for the purpose of complying with government disclosure requirements, subpoenas, search warrants, applicable laws or other lawful requests for information or where EyeWonder believes disclosure is otherwise necessary to establish, exercise or defend legal rights
  2. With vendors, services providers and other technology providers that act on EyeWonder's behalf to enable it to provide services to its clients
  3. With other members of the EyeWonder group of companies for internal reporting purposes and so that they may provide services to their clients
  4. For any other lawful purpose.

_B. Cookies_

EyeWonder uses "cookies" or "scripts" to enhance a user's experience on the Internet. A cookie is a small text file served by EyeWonder and stored by a user's web browser. It contains a unique number that is assigned to a browser by EyeWonder the first time an EyeWonder®-powered advertisement is served or a user visits the Site. This number is stored on the user's computer and helps deliver advertisements which are not repetitive and may be more relevant to the user. This number cannot be transferred to another browser, cannot be related to a specific person, and does not contain viruses. Additionally cookies may collect the types of information about users described in this Part 2, although this will not include any information that enables any user to be identified as an individual. Users can adjust their Internet browser settings to disable or delete the use of cookies and scripts; however, some functionalities of an EyeWonder®-powered advertisement or the Site may not be available without the use of cookies and scripts. As the means by which users can do this vary from browser-to-browser, users should visit their browser's help menu for further details. EyeWonder also offers users the ability to refuse the placement of EyeWonder cookies for the purpose of serving rich media or targeted advertising, as described in Part 1, section D headed 'User choices' above.

EyeWonder sets cookies to expire after eight weeks and the expiration date updates every time a user encounters the EyeWonder server.

_C. International processing_

EyeWonder operates the Site, and collects information about users that choose to visit the Site, on servers hosted in the United States of America. Users' information will always be protected in accordance with strict data security standards.

_D. Other websites_

This Part 2 applies solely to the EyeWonder Site. EyeWonder is not responsible for the privacy practices of advertisers, publishers, networks, portals, or other sites to which the Site may link.

**Updates and Questions**

Changes in EyeWonder's Privacy Policy may occur at any time. Such changes will be communicated by publishing the modified Privacy Policy on the Site. Please be sure to check for updates. While changes may be made to the Privacy Policy, EyeWonder will not use personally identifiable information for any new purposes without user consent.

This privacy policy was last updated on May 2, 2012.

**Contact Us**  
Any questions or concerns regarding these policies or practices should be directed to:

**EyeWonder, LLC**  
229 Peachtree Street, NE  
International Tower, Suite 1700  
Atlanta, GA 30303  
Phone: (678) 891-2020  
Fax: (678) 891-2017
